<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
<title>Pacific Rim: Jaeger Deployments</title>
    <author>
        <name>Jonathan Chen</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://clamhead939.tumblr.com/</id>
    <updated>2013-11-24T20:01:16.403-08:00</updated>
    <entry>
        <title>Coyote Tango</title>
        <id>http://pacificrim.wikia.com/wiki/Coyote_Tango</id>
        <category term="Mark-1"/><content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>Coyote Tango is the second tallest of the Mark-1 Jaegers (behind Cherno Alpha), designed to resemble naval warships and Cobra attack helicopters in both color scheme and appearance.[1] Coyote Tango's light armor allows it to perform various deadly maneuvers and has great speed to evade Kaiju attacks. It is also armed with twin long-range ballistic mortar cannons to damage Kaiju from afar; these were supplemented by a forearm-mounted, retractable V-PI EnergyCaster with five modes of modulation - this weapon in particular being considered highly experimental at the time of the Jaeger's launch.
        As a Mark-1 Jaeger, Coyote Tango runs on the power of a nuclear reactor. Given the short amount of time the Pan Pacific Defense Corps had to build the first series of Jaegers in response to the Kaiju threat, none of the Mark-1 series Jaegers were reinforced with protective measures to prevent radiation poisoning. As a result, the Rangers piloting Mark-1's developed cancer-related illnesses from exposure. Coyote Tango's pilots, Tamsin Sevier and Stacker Pentecost developed cancer from the exposure to the Jaeger's nuclear reactor. Both were retired from active duty as a result of their exposure to the reactor.</p></div></content>
        <link href="http://pacificrim.wikia.com/wiki/Coyote_Tango"/>
        <updated>2005-12-30T18:48:54.49-08:00</updated>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Gipsy Danger</title>
        <id>http://pacificrim.wikia.com/wiki/Gipsy_Danger</id>
        <category term="Mark-3"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>Gipsy Danger's appearance, faded blue paint job and romanticized decal, invokes the visual design fighter aircraft like Vought F4U Corsair from the World War II era. Its body language is largely dominated by Raleigh, regardless of his co-pilot, reflecting his unpredictable nature and ability to adapt to combat situations. Because Gipsy Danger's head is detachable from its body, large flaps stemming from its shoulders protect the back of its head and the base of the neck where the body connects with the Conn-Pod.
        Gipsy's 08FS/Oceanic Cooling vents maintain temperature and channel seawater through the circulatory coolant system; 98BD/Hyper-Torque Drives allow Gipsy Danger's muscle strands increased locomotion. Gipsy's Nuclear Vortex Turbine maintains health checks and returned radio chemical readings in excess of safety parameters. The turbine can also be utilized to fire a directed heat weapon powerful enough to puncture completely through a grappling Kaiju when fired at point blank range. Gipsy Danger possesses a gauntlet-fixed S-11 Pulse Launcher, which fires an orb of pure dark matter at its target; successful strikes tend to disrupt the molecular structure of Kaiju biology.</p>
            </div>
        </content
        ><link href="http://pacificrim.wikia.com/wiki/Gipsy_Danger"/>
        <updated>2007-07-10T05:31:17-08:00</updated>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Crimson Typhoon</title>
        <id>http://pacificrim.wikia.com/wiki/Crimson_Typhoon</id>
        <category term="Mark-4"/><content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
            <p>Unique among the Jaegers, Crimson Typhoon is piloted by three Rangers as opposed to the traditional two. The Conn-Pod, designed by Dr. Caitlin Lightcap, functions and accommodates a triple Neural Handshake and three-pilot control. Two pilots to control the Jaeger's basic movements in the front, and a third pilot to act as gunner behind his co-pilots.
        Crimson is constructed with full titanium core alloys and fifty diesel engine per muscle strand. Crimson Typhoon's three arms allow for great mobility and range in combat; the fighting style of the Wei Tang triplets grant Crimson the grace of a practiced martial artist. Broad shouldered, Crimson Typhoon uses its shoulders to defend against punches and shield itself, allowing it to strike back immediately, rolling with the left shoulder. It also features three rear jets which allows for an increase in forward movement for a limited amount of time. They can be used to aid in the the Jaeger's ability to leap into the air, often decreasing the distance between her and a kaiju to land a melee attack. These rear jets can ignite independently of each other increasing the speed of its melee strikes, as the torso twists during the slashing movement of the Jaeger's arms. They can be seen during Crimson Typhoon's signature attack, "Thundercloud Formation".</p>
        </div>
        </content>
        <link href="http://pacificrim.wikia.com/wiki/Crimson_Typhoon"/><updated>2008-08-22T06:14:11-08:00</updated></entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Romeo Blue</title>
        <id>http://pacificrim.wikia.com/wiki/Romeo_Blue</id>
        <category term="Mark-1"/>
        <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
            <p>Like most Mark-1 Jaegers, Romeo Blue is powered by a nuclear reactor. Its armament is primarily long range; its Gatling Chest allows it to attack Kaiju from a distance. "Tracheal Break" is one of its signature moves. Romeo Blue is one of the slowest Jaegers made because of its immense weight, having one fifth of the speed of Striker Eureka.
        Romeo Blue has a wide body and two small fins at the back similar to the T-16 Angel Wings on Striker Eureka. Romeo Blue's head is small and bears a crest at the top, the visor is thin and is symmetrical on either side of the head. Its hands are rounded and it has short fingers. The lower torso of Romeo Blue is quite thin before it gets wider for the hips and legs. A large and distinctive vertical fin-like structure protrudes from the center of the Jaeger's chest and was designed to protect the Conn-Pod from attack.</p>
        </div>
        </content>
        <link href="http://pacificrim.wikia.com/wiki/Romeo_Blue"/>
        <updated>2005-12-15T03:18:11-08:00</updated>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Striker Eureka</title>
        <id>http://pacificrim.wikia.com/wiki/Striker_Eureka</id>
        <category term="Mark-5"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>The strongest of the Jaegers, Striker Eureka's fighting style is akin to that of a dirty boxer or brutal brawler; stemming primarily from its pilots, Chuck and Herc Hansen's fighting style. Striker Eureka's speed and agility allow it to combat and kill Kaiju far quicker than the previous Jaeger series produced, its T-16 Angel Wings acting as stabilizers to maintain aerodynamic balance during the turbulence of burst combat.
        Striker's six-barreled WMB2x90 Anti-Kaiju Missile chest launcher is equipped with eighteen individual K-Stunner warheads that kill Kaiju with a direct hit. Striker Eureka contains a TY escape pod in the back of its Conn-Pod, allowing pilots to eject in the face of defeat; and a escape hatch at the top of its head akin to that of Coyote Tango. Lastly, the Striker's 90ER11 amber platinum visor is equipped with advanced photochromic displays, allowing four planes of situational awareness.</p>
            </div>
        </content>
        <link href="http://pacificrim.wikia.com/wiki/Striker_Eureka"/>
        <updated>2009-11-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Horizon Brave</title>
        <id>http://pacificrim.wikia.com/wiki/Horizon_Brave</id>
        <category term="Mark-1"/>
        <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
            <p>As a Mark-1 series Jaeger, Horizon Brave is among the first Jaegers constructed on Kodiak Island, Alaska when the Jaeger Program was greenlit by the Pan Pacific Defense Corps. Horizon Brave is deployed in combat alongside Romeo Blue, Tacit Ronin, and Coyote Tango.
        Horizon Brave is armed with cryo cannons mounted to its shoulders, used to freeze Kaiju in battle or power its melee attacks. "Sub-zero suckerpunch" and  "Flash freeze" are two of its signature attacks. Like all Mark-1 Jaegers, Horizon Brave is powered by a nuclear reactor.</p>
        </div>
        </content>
        <link href="http://pacificrim.wikia.com/wiki/Horizon_Brave"/>
        <updated>2005-12-02T07:57:29-08:00</updated>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Tacit Ronin</title>
        <id>http://pacificrim.wikia.com/wiki/Tacit_Ronin</id>
        <category term="Mark-1"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>Similar to Coyote Tango, Tacit Ronin is lightly armored allowing for quicker movement and greater speed to evade any Kaiju attacks. Tacit Ronin is powered by a nuclear reactor and is armed with a pair of Fangblades mounted under each wrist, designed for close combat.
        When not in use the Fangblades retract backwards, with the blade tip retreating behind Tacit Ronin's fists. "Cobra Strike" is one of its signature attack moves. Tacit Ronin also has two rear jets along the center of the back most likely to increase its propulsion for quick bursts, such as Gipsy Danger and Crimson Typhoon.</p>
            </div>
        </content>
        <link href="http://pacificrim.wikia.com/wiki/Tacit_Ronin"/>
        <updated>2005-12-06T18:56:34-08:00</updated>
    </entry>
</feed>
