<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
   <title>My Favorite Movies</title>
   <link href="http://people.ischool.berkeley.edu/~haroon/my-favorite-movies/my-favorite-movies.atom"
         rel="self"/>
   <id>http://people.ischool.berkeley.edu/~haroon/my-favorite-movies/my-favorite-movies.atom</id>
   <updated>2013-11-22T19:57:18.655-08:00</updated>
   <author>
      <name>Haroon Rasheed</name>
      <uri>http://people.ischool.berkeley.edu/~haroon/</uri>
   </author>
   <entry>
      <updated>2013-11-01T17:38:41Z</updated>
      <title>Nayakan</title>
      <id>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0093603/?ref_=rvi_tt</id>
      <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0093603/?ref_=rvi_tt"/>
      <content>Nayakan (English: The Hero), also known as Nayagan, is a 1987 Indian Tamil crime film, written and directed by Mani Ratnam and starring Kamal Haasan. It is based on the real-life Bombay underworld don Varada aka Varadarajan Mudaliar, and sympathetically depicts the struggle of South Indians living in Bombay. </content>
   </entry>
   <entry>
      <updated>2013-11-02T17:38:41Z</updated>
      <title>Pulp Fiction</title>
      <id>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110912/?ref_=rvi_tt</id>
      <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110912/?ref_=rvi_tt"/>
      <content>Pulp Fiction is a 1994 American crime film directed by Quentin Tarantino, who also co-wrote the screenplay along with Roger Avary.[4] The film is known for its eclectic dialogue, ironic mix of humor and violence, nonlinear storyline, and a host of cinematic allusions and pop culture references. The film was nominated for seven Oscars, including Best Picture; Tarantino and Avary won for Best Original Screenplay.</content>
   </entry>
   <entry>
      <updated>2013-11-01T17:40:41Z</updated>
      <title>Thevar Magan</title>
      <id>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0105575/?ref_=rvi_tt</id>
      <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0105575/?ref_=rvi_tt"/>
      <content>Thevar Magan (English: Son of the Thevar) is a 1992 Indian Tamil film produced, written and starring Kamal Hassan in the title role. It was directed by Bharathan and also stars Sivaji Ganesan, Nassar, Revathi and Gouthami in pivotal roles. The film score and soundtrack are composed by Ilaiyaraaja. </content>
   </entry>
   <entry>
      <updated>2013-11-01T17:42:41Z</updated>
      <title>The Godfather</title>
      <id>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0068646/?ref_=rvi_tt</id>
      <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0068646/?ref_=rvi_tt"/>
      <content>The Godfather is a 1972 American crime film directed by Francis Ford Coppola and produced by Albert S. Ruddy from a screenplay by Mario Puzo and Coppola. Based on Puzo's 1969 novel of the same name, the film stars Marlon Brando and Al Pacino as the leaders of a fictional New York crime family. </content>
   </entry>
   <entry>
      <updated>2013-11-01T17:44:41Z</updated>
      <title>Hey Ram</title>
      <id>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0222012/?ref_=rvi_tt</id>
      <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0222012/?ref_=rvi_tt"/>
      <content>Hey Ram (translation: Oh Ram! or Oh God!) is a bilingual Tamil and Hindi film. It also had a simultaneously produced Hindi version and was released in 2000. The film was written, directed and produced by Kamal Haasan and he also starred as the protagonist in the film.</content>
   </entry>
   <entry>
      <updated>2013-11-01T17:46:41Z</updated>
      <title>Forrest Gump</title>
      <id>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109830/</id>
      <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109830/"/>
      <content>Forrest Gump is a 1994 American epic romantic comedy-drama film based on the 1986 novel of the same name by Winston Groom. The film was directed by Robert Zemeckis and starred Tom Hanks, Robin Wright, Gary Sinise and Sally Field.</content>
   </entry>
   <entry>
      <updated>2013-11-01T17:48:41Z</updated>
      <title>Aaranya Kaandam</title>
      <id>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1496729/?ref_=rvi_tt</id>
      <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1496729/?ref_=rvi_tt"/>
      <content>Aaranya Kaandam (Tamil: ஆரண்ய காண்டம்; English: Jungle chapter; English title: Anima and Persona)[2] is a 2011 Indian Tamil action film, written and directed by newcomer Thiagarajan Kumararaja. It is supposedly the first neo-noir film in Tamil cinema.</content>
   </entry>
   <entry>
      <updated>2013-11-01T17:50:41Z</updated>
      <title>Inception</title>
      <id>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1375666/?ref_=rvi_tt</id>
      <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1375666/?ref_=rvi_tt"/>
      <content>Inception is a 2010 science fiction film written, co-produced, and directed by Christopher Nolan. The film stars a large ensemble cast that includes Leonardo DiCaprio, Ken Watanabe, Joseph Gordon-Levitt, Marion Cotillard, Ellen Page, Tom Hardy, Dileep Rao, Cillian Murphy, Tom Berenger, and Michael Caine. </content>
   </entry>
   <entry>
      <updated>2013-11-01T17:54:41Z</updated>
      <title>Rang De Basanti</title>
      <id>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0405508/?ref_=rvi_tt</id>
      <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0405508/?ref_=rvi_tt"/>
      <content>Rang De Basanti (IPA: [ˈrəŋɡ d̪eː bəˈsənt̪i]; English: "Colour it Saffron" or "Paint it Yellow") is a 2006 Indian drama film written and directed by Rakeysh Omprakash Mehra. It features an ensemble cast comprising Aamir Khan, Siddharth Narayan, Soha Ali Khan, Kunal Kapoor, Madhavan, Sharman Joshi, Atul Kulkarni and British actress Alice Patten in the lead roles. </content>
   </entry>
   <entry>
      <updated>2013-11-01T17:57:41Z</updated>
      <title>Dil Chahta Hai</title>
      <id>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0292490/?ref_=rvi_tt</id>
      <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0292490/?ref_=rvi_tt"/>
      <content>Dil Chahta Hai (Hindī: दिल चाहता है, English: The Heart Desires, but billed as Do Your Thing) is a 2001 Indian coming-of-age comedy-drama film starring Aamir Khan, Saif Ali Khan, Akshaye Khanna, Preity Zinta, Sonali Kulkarni, and Dimple Kapadia. </content>
   </entry>
</feed>
