<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><atom:feed xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us"><atom:updated>2013-11-22T10:00:00-05:00</atom:updated><atom:title>Paul's Library Feed</atom:title><atom:link href="http://www.example.com" rel="self"/><atom:author><atom:name>Paul Son</atom:name><atom:email>pcson@ischool.berkeley.edu</atom:email></atom:author><atom:id>http://www.example.org/pcson</atom:id><atom:entry><atom:updated>2013-11-20T10:00:00-05:00</atom:updated><atom:title>A Treatise of Human Understanding</atom:title><atom:link href="http://www.example.com/pcson/2013/11/21/book" rel="alternate"/><atom:id>http://www.example.org/pcson01</atom:id><atom:summary>A Treatise of Human Nature is a book by Scottish philosopher David Hume, first published in 1739–1740.
        The full title of the Treatise is 'A Treatise of Human Nature: Being an Attempt to introduce the experimental Method 
        of Reasoning into Moral Subjects'. It contains the following sections: Book 1: "Of the Understanding" – An investigation 
        into human cognition. Important statements of Skepticism. Book 2: "Of the Passions" – A treatment of emotions and free 
        will. Book 3: "Of Morals" – A treatment of moral ideas, justice, obligations, benevolence</atom:summary><atom:author><atom:name>
            David
            Hume
        :  </atom:name></atom:author></atom:entry><atom:entry><atom:updated>2013-10-18T10:00:00-05:00</atom:updated><atom:title>Batman: Hush</atom:title><atom:link href="http://www.example.com/pcson/2013/11/21/book" rel="alternate"/><atom:id>http://www.example.org/pcson02</atom:id><atom:summary>BATMAN: HUSH is a thrilling mystery of action, intrigue, and deception penned by Jeph Loeb (BATMAN: THE LONG HALLOWEEN)
        and illustrated by comics superstar Jim Lee (ALL STAR BATMAN &amp; ROBIN, THE BOY WONDER) in which Batman sets out to discover the 
        identity of a mysterious mastermind using the Joker, Riddler, Ra's al Ghul and the Dark Knight's other enemies - and allies - 
        as pawns in a plan to wreak havoc.</atom:summary><atom:author><atom:name>
            Jim
            Lee
        :  </atom:name></atom:author></atom:entry><atom:entry><atom:updated>2013-09-22T10:00:00-05:00</atom:updated><atom:title>Responsibility and the Moral Sentiments</atom:title><atom:link href="http://www.example.com/pcson/2013/11/21/book" rel="alternate"/><atom:id>http://www.example.org/pcson03</atom:id><atom:summary>R. Jay Wallace advances a powerful and sustained argument against the common view that accountability requires freedom of will. 
        Instead, he maintains, the fairness of holding people responsible depends on their rational competence: the power to grasp moral reasons 
        and to control their behavior accordingly. He shows how these forms of rational competence are compatible with determinism. At the same 
        time, giving serious consideration to incompatibilist concerns, Wallace develops a compelling diagnosis of the common assumption that 
        freedom is necessary for responsibility.</atom:summary><atom:author><atom:name>
            Dr.
            R.
            Jay
            Wallace
        :  </atom:name></atom:author></atom:entry><atom:entry><atom:updated>2013-05-22T10:00:00-05:00</atom:updated><atom:title>The Republic</atom:title><atom:link href="http://www.example.com/pcson/2013/11/21/book" rel="alternate"/><atom:id>http://www.example.org/pcson04</atom:id><atom:summary>Famous philosophical treatise of the 4th century BC concerns itself chiefly with the idea of justice, as well as such Platonic theories 
        as that of ideas, the criticism of poetry, and the philosopher's role. Source of the famous cave myth and prototype for other imaginary commonwealths, 
        including those of Cicero, St. Augustine, and More</atom:summary><atom:author><atom:name>
            Plato
        :  </atom:name></atom:author></atom:entry><atom:entry><atom:updated>2013-01-22T10:00:00-05:00</atom:updated><atom:title>The Discipline of Organizing</atom:title><atom:link href="http://www.example.com/pcson/2013/11/21/book" rel="alternate"/><atom:id>http://www.example.org/pcson05</atom:id><atom:summary>This book offers a framework for the theory and practice of organizing that integrates information organization (IO) and information retrieval (IR),
        bridging the disciplinary chasms between Library and Information Science and Computer Science, each of which views and teaches IO and IR as separate topics 
        and in substantially different ways</atom:summary><atom:author><atom:name>
            Robert
            Glushko 
        :  </atom:name></atom:author></atom:entry><atom:entry><atom:updated>2012-12-22T10:00:00-05:00</atom:updated><atom:title>Momofuku</atom:title><atom:link href="http://www.example.com/pcson/2013/11/21/book" rel="alternate"/><atom:id>http://www.example.org/pcson06</atom:id><atom:summary>Never before has there been a phenomenon like Momofuku. A once-unrecognizable word, 
        it's now synonymous with the award-winning restaurants of the same name in New York City: Momofuku Noodle Bar, 
        Ssäm Bar, Ko, and Milk Bar. Chef David Chang has single-handedly revolutionized cooking in America with his use of bold Asian 
        flavors and impeccable ingredients, his mastery of the humble ramen noodle, and his thorough devotion to pork</atom:summary><atom:author><atom:name>
            Chef
            David
            Chang
        :  </atom:name></atom:author></atom:entry><atom:entry><atom:updated>2012-11-22T10:00:00-05:00</atom:updated><atom:title>The Problem of Evil</atom:title><atom:link href="http://www.example.com/pcson/2013/11/21/book" rel="alternate"/><atom:id>http://www.example.org/pcson07</atom:id><atom:summary>Many reflective people are convinced that the problem, the problem of evil, is insoluble. The reasons that underlie this conviction can be 
        formulated as a powerful argument for the non-existence of God, the so-called argument from evil: If there were a God, he would not permit the existence 
        of vast amounts of truly horrible suffering; since such suffering exists, there is no God. Peter van Inwagen examines this argument, which he regards as 
        a paradigmatically philosophical argument. </atom:summary><atom:author><atom:name>
               Dr.
               Peter
               van Inwagen
           :  </atom:name></atom:author></atom:entry></atom:feed>