<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<assignments xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
	<course link="../">IoT Spring 2015</course>
	<assignment-css-uri>../spring15.css</assignment-css-uri>
	<assignment-base-uri>http://dret.net/lectures/iot-spring15/a/</assignment-base-uri>
	<html-author-block>Instructors: Simon Mayer, Florian Michahelles, and <a href="http://dret.net/netdret/">Erik Wilde</a></html-author-block>
	<html-footer>
		<hr/>
		<table border="0" width="100%">
			<tr>
				<td align="left" style="padding-right : 5px">
					<a xmlns:cc="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/" rel="cc:license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" class="img">
						<img alt="Creative Commons License" title="This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License" border="0" src="../../img/somerights20.png" height="31" width="88"/>
					</a>
				</td>
				<td align="left" width="100%">
					<span class="footnote">Please send comments to <a href="mailto:dret@berkeley.edu">dret@berkeley.edu</a>
						<br/>Last modification: <!--#echo var="LAST_MODIFIED" -->
					</span>
				</td>
				<td align="right">
					<a href="http://jigsaw.w3.org/css-validator" class="img">
						<img src="../../img/vcss.gif" height="31" width="88" border="0" alt="valid CSS!" title="valid CSS!"/>
					</a>
				</td>
				<td>
					<a href="http://validator.w3.org/check/referer" class="img">
						<img src="../../img/vxhtml10.gif" height="31" width="88" border="0" alt="valid XHTML 1.0!" title="valid XHTML 1.0!"/>
					</a>
				</td>
			</tr>
		</table>
	</html-footer>
	<assignment>
		<title>Internetworking Things</title>
		<dates assigned="2015-01-30" due="2015-02-05"/>
		<abstract>As a simple and easy way to interconnect things, we build sample applications with <a href="http://nodered.org/">Node-RED</a>. Node-RED is an open source browser-based tool for wiring together hardware devices, APIs and online services in new and interesting ways.</abstract>
		<instructions>
			<p><a href="http://nodered.org/">Node-RED</a></p>
			<p><a href="http://flows.nodered.org/">Node-RED flow library</a></p>
		</instructions>
	</assignment>
	<assignment>
		<title>Internet/Web Basics</title>
		<dates assigned="2015-02-06" due="2015-02-12"/>
		<abstract>Moving closer to the core of the IoT and WoT, we establish HTTP connections and send different kinds of HTTP requests. We also get to know libraries to use for these purposes, HTTP content negotiation and a few HTTP headers and response codes. We parse and display simple content in a smartphone application, using 3rd party libraries.</abstract>
		<instructions>
			<p>...</p>
		</instructions>
	</assignment>
	<assignment>
		<title>Project Proposals</title>
		<dates assigned="2015-02-13" due="2015-02-15"/>
		<abstract>Everyone develops and formulates an individual project idea for the lab lightning talks.</abstract>
		<instructions>
			<p>...</p>
		</instructions>
	</assignment>
	<assignment>
		<title>Project Development</title>
		<dates assigned="2015-02-20" due="2015-02-26"/>
		<abstract>Project group formation and development of a more concrete description of the project. This includes a detailed list of sources for input data, targets for outputs, how this data maps to activities, and what the detailed meaning of the data is with respect to the project scenario.</abstract>
		<instructions>
			<p>...</p>
		</instructions>
	</assignment>
	<assignment>
		<title>Activity Vocabulary Development</title>
		<dates assigned="2015-02-27" due="2015-03-05"/>
		<abstract>Our Activity Streams platform ASbase is using Activity Streams as its data model. This assignment is about developing a vocabulary that is sufficient to represent the data that is required to make the group project work. The vocabulary that is used for conveying activities which are relevant to the scenario should be formalized in this step. Also, examples for concrete activities that are exchanged during the scenario should be given.</abstract>
		<instructions>
			<p>AS vocabularies can be developed and modeled in many different ways, even when looking at the same scenario. As general guidelines, keep the following aspects in mind:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>The activity (the verb) should be specific enough so that it conveys meaningful information about what happened, so that consumers can use it to filter for the activities they do and do not want to process.</li>
				<li>The activity (the verb) should be general enough so that it is not only useful for the one specific scenario, but has potential for reuse in other scenarios as well.</li>
				<li>The activity should be accompanied by metadata that allows consumers to further narrow their selection of activities that the do or do not want to process.</li>
				<li>If possible, try to design the activity metadata in a way so that there is potential for reuse across different activities (i.e., verbs).</li>
			</ul>
		</instructions>
	</assignment>
	<assignment>
		<title>Getting Data into ASbase</title>
		<dates assigned="2015-03-06" due="2015-03-19"/>
		<abstract>Based on the vocabulary, in this assignment data sources (either APIs or networked things) are used to get information, convert it into Activity Streams, and then submit it to ASbase to that it can be used by ASbase consumers.</abstract>
		<instructions>
			<p>...</p>
		</instructions>
	</assignment>
	<assignment>
		<title>Getting Data out of ASbase</title>
		<dates assigned="2015-03-20" due="2015-04-09"/>
		<abstract>In this assignment, activity streams that are distributed by the platform should be consumed by ASbase clients. These can for instance be analysis modules or user interfaces/dashboards. The goal is to have an up-and-running prototype implementation of the project idea by the end of this assignment.</abstract>
		<instructions>
			<p>...</p>
		</instructions>
	</assignment>
	<assignment>
		<title>Mixing Groups: Scenario Mashups</title>
		<dates assigned="2015-04-10" due="2015-04-16"/>
		<abstract>Each group should coordinate with others with the goal of making use of their information within your own scenario. This will involve negotiating how to use and align the (perhaps differing) vocabularies.</abstract>
		<instructions>
			<p>...</p>
		</instructions>
	</assignment>
	<assignment>
		<title>Planning and Building the Mashup</title>
		<dates assigned="2015-04-17" due="2015-04-30"/>
		<abstract>Each group shall implement a mashup that is based on data from your own sources and from at least one other group, with the ASbase platform as the central coordinator.</abstract>
		<instructions>
			<p>...</p>
		</instructions>
	</assignment>
</assignments>
