<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="hotspot/hotspot/hotspot.xsl"?>
<?hotspot layout-path="hotspot/hotspot/layout" ?>
<?hotspot kilauea-path="hotspot/kilauea" ?>
<?hotspot layout="malmoe" ?>
<hotspot xmlns="http://dret.net/xmlns/hotspot/1" xmlns:hotspot="http://dret.net/xmlns/hotspot/1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://dret.net/xmlns/hotspot/1 hotspot/hotspot/schemas/hotspot.xsd">
	<configuration>
		<link subsections="yes" bookmarks="yes" versions="iot-ornl-2015.xml" home="./" help="quick" contents="./" author="http://dret.net/netdret/"/>
		<paths img="img" listing="src"/>
		<outline count-text=" [*]" count-depth="all"/>
		<hyperlink extra=""/>
		<extension file="html" link=""/>
		<counter separator=":&#160;"/>
		<kilauea xmlns="http://xmlns.sharpeleven.net/kilauea">
			<plugins>
				<touch/>
			</plugins>
		</kilauea>
	</configuration>
	<license uri="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" short="CC 3.0">
		<div class="license">
			<p><a rel="license" title="view full text of license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/"><img alt="Creative Commons License" src="hotspot/hotspot/layout/ischool/ischool/somerights20.png" border="0" height="31" width="88"/></a></p>
			<p><a class="outlink" rel="license" title="view full text of license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">This work is licensed under a CC<br/>Attribution 3.0 Unported License</a></p>
		</div>
	</license>
	<title><a href="https://www.ornl.gov/" title="Oak Ridge National Laboratory">ORNL</a> IoT Workshop</title>
	<author><a href="http://dret.net/netdret/">Erik Wilde</a></author>
	<affiliation>UC Berkeley</affiliation>
	<date short="2015-08-07">August 7, 2015</date>
	<copyright>2015 Erik Wilde</copyright>
	<presentation id="index">
		<title>WoT IoT Needs</title>
		<slide id="abstract">
			<title>Abstract</title>
			<p class="abstract">The Internet of Things (IoT) is one of the hot topics in research and industry, and yet there seem to be very different ways in which the name can be interpreted, ranging from low-level connectivity issues up through all protocol layers. This talk makes the point that IoT today can be viewed like the Internet in its early days, which clearly was useful and growing, but needed the Web as the killer app to get to the growth and significance that define it today. In the same way as the Web allowed the Internet to break through previously existing barriers, the Web of Things (WoT) may be able to accomplish the same for IoT. By looking at some of the critical features that allowed the Web to succeed at levels previously impossible for the Internet, we may be able to predict some of the areas where WoT approaches may achieve the same for IoT scenarios.</p>
		</slide>
		<part>
			<title>(Some) Internet/Web History</title>
			<slide>
				<title>From Growth to Explosion</title>
				<ul>
					<li>The Internet <a href="http://www.internetsociety.org/internet/what-internet/history-internet/brief-history-internet">started growing in the late 1970s</a></li>
					<ul>
						<li>TCP/IP established robust and reliable global connectivity</li>
						<li>Successful applications were email and file transfer</li>
						<li>Internet as <em>connection infrastructure</em> and not <em>information infrastructure</em></li>
					</ul>
					<li>The pre-Web Internet was always point-to-point</li>
					<li>Applications had specialized and specific interfaces</li>
					<li>1989, the Web dissolved application boundaries</li>
					<ul>
						<li>Different services/applications could be interlinked</li>
						<li>The same client could be used to interact with all of them</li>
					</ul>
				</ul>
			</slide>
			<slide>
				<title>Historical Internet Traffic (1993-2004)</title>
				<img src="internet-traffic-trends.png" style="height : 65% ; margin : 4% ; " href="http://dret.net/lectures/web-fall10/http#%284%29"/>
			</slide>
			<slide>
				<title>Simplicity as the Price for Unification</title>
				<ul>
					<li><q>Network effect</q> trumps polished verticals</li>
					<ul>
						<li>Web pages were rather limited for a long time</li>
						<li>Interlinking and ubiquitous clients compensated for that (<q>Service Fusion</q>)</li>
					</ul>
					<li>IoT today is mostly at the pre-Web Internet stage</li>
					<ul>
						<li>Well-defined and limited application domains</li>
						<li>Specialized services that can only be consumed by specialized clients</li>
					</ul>
					<li>Today's <em>apps</em> are the ghosts of pre-Web client/server approaches</li>
					<ul>
						<li>Tailored/convenient to do one thing in one silo</li>
						<li><em>App management</em> is a well-known problem for providers/consumers</li>
					</ul>
				</ul>
			</slide>
		</part>
		<part id="iot-problems">
			<title>IoT Problems Today</title>
			<slide>
				<title>Invisibility</title>
				<ul>
					<li>No Web-level identification of resources/services</li>
					<ul>
						<li>URIs often are resolvable HTTP URIs but don't have to be</li>
						<li>Identification (even without interaction) creates a lot of value</li>
						<li>Identity and identification are hard problems for real-world resources</li>
					</ul>
					<li><em>Data Fusion</em> works best with known and managed identifiers</li>
					<li>Robust naming schemes are needed for all WoT scenarios</li>
					<ul>
						<li>The network effect needs relatable identifiers</li>
						<li>Actionable identifiers are a (big) plus but not strictly required</li>
					</ul>
				</ul>
			</slide>
			<slide>
				<title>Discoverability</title>
				<ul>
					<li>No easy way to find existing (i.e., identified) resources</li>
					<ul>
						<li>Will there be a <q>Google for the IoT</q>? How would it work in today's/tomorrow's WoT?</li>
						<li>Something similar to <a href="http://schema.org/">schema.org</a> may be necessary/helpful</li>
					</ul>
					<li>Discovery in IoT probably also needs a robust update channel</li>
					<ul>
						<li>The set of discovered resources can change a lot over time</li>
						<li><q>Subscribing</q> to change messages allows clients to stay updated</li>
					</ul>
				</ul>
			</slide>
			<slide>
				<title>Siloization</title>
				<ul>
					<li>Many IoT scenarios are tightly controlled verticals</li>
					<ul>
						<li>Easier to design and implement for vendors (engineering legacy)</li>
						<li>Easier to control and monetize (walled gardens are profitable)</li>
					</ul>
					<li>A lot of value can be created by working across silo boundaries</li>
					<ul>
						<li><em>Avoid</em> <q>warehouse</q> approaches selling centralized <q>integration</q></li>
						<li><em>Prefer</em> ecosystem approaches that with a decentralized architecture</li>
					</ul>
				</ul>
			</slide>
			<slide>
				<title>Precious Snowflakes (aka NIH)</title>
				<ul>
					<li>Starting from scratch often is easier than reuse</li>
					<ul>
						<li>Many existing designs are not well-documented and extensible</li>
						<li>In many cases there is no incentive to reuse</li>
					</ul>
					<li>Defining domain models can be hard work</li>
					<ul>
						<li>W3C should stay away from specific domains and focus on the connective fabric</li>
						<li>Domain models should be left to domain experts and their organizations</li>
					</ul>
				</ul>
			</slide>
		</part>
		<part id="web-architecture">
			<title>Web Architecture</title>
			<slide>
				<title>What <em>is</em> the Web?</title>
				<ul>
					<li>Three pillars are required for something to be truly webby</li>
					<ul>
						<li>Global Identification</li>
						<li>Uniform and Stateless Interaction</li>
						<li>Self-describing and linked representations</li>
					</ul>
					<li>W3C is trying to establish best practices</li>
					<ul>
						<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/WoT/IG/">Web of Things Interest Group (WoT IG)</a></li>
						<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/dwbp/">Data on the Web Best Practices</a></li>
						<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/sdw-ucr/">Spatial Data on the Web Use Cases &amp; Requirements</a></li>
					</ul>
					<li>Lots of work to be done and more Web expertise required</li>
					<ul>
						<li>Finding the sweet spot for value creation</li>
					</ul>
				</ul>
			</slide>
			<slide>
				<title>What's Different About Web/WoT?</title>
				<ul>
					<li><em>Data Science</em> often assumes centralized data management</li>
					<li>The Web is not only <em>distributed</em>, it is <em>decentralized</em></li>
					<li>Embrace the Big Data Vs:</li>
					<ul>
						<li><em>Volume:</em> Working <q>on a dataset</q> not always (easily) possible</li>
						<li><em>Velocity:</em> A robust model for how to do (incremental) updates</li>
						<li><em>Variety:</em> Handling data in a variety of models/metamodels</li>
						<li><em>Variability:</em> Variations in meaning may need contextual analysis</li>
					</ul>
					<li>The Web focuses on <em>interaction/service models</em>, not <em>data models</em></li>
					<ul>
						<li>Describe as little as possible (only the <q>service surface</q>)</li>
					</ul>
				</ul>
			</slide>
			<slide>
				<title>Industry vs. Web</title>
				<ul>
					<li>Industry wants to package and sell</li>
					<ul>
						<li>One integrated and elegant solution for one scenario and/or vertical</li>
						<li>Also allows relatively easy client-side toolkits/libraries</li>
					</ul>
					<li>Users want to ignore provider-specific things as much as possible</li>
					<ul>
						<li>IoT has a lot of <q>works best/only in IE</q> feel to it these days</li>
						<li>Loose coupling means some client-side work is required</li>
					</ul>
				</ul>
			</slide>
		</part>
		<part id="data-and-services">
			<title>Web Data and Web Services</title>
			<slide id="web-data">
				<title>Web Data</title>
				<ul>
					<li>Any IoT resources/services should be <q>webby</q> by design</li>
					<li><a href="https://github.com/dret/webdata">Web Data</a> follows five simple principles</li>
					<ol>
						<li>★: Linkable (use URI for identification)</li>
						<li>★★: Parseable (use existing <span title="such as XML, RDF, JSON, CSV">metamodels</span> if possible)</li>
						<li>★★★: Understandable (document the model/vocabulary)</li>
						<li>★★★★: Linked (relate to other resources by URI)</li>
						<li>★★★★★: Usable (communicate how your resources can be used)</li>
					</ol>
					<li><em>Web Data</em> is REST without the service parts: data on the Web should be hypermedia</li>
					<ul>
						<li>REST calls this <q title="Hypermedia as the engine of application state">HATEOAS</q> and adds behavioral constraints</li>
					</ul>
				</ul>
			</slide>
			<slide>
				<title>A WoT Service Model</title>
				<ul>
					<li><a href="http://activitystrea.ms/">Activity Streams (AS)</a> were invented for social services</li>
					<ul>
						<li>A model for social activities/actors across various social platforms</li>
						<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/Social/WG">W3C Social Web WG</a> has been chartered to standardize AS2</li>
					</ul>
					<li><a href="http://dret.net/netdret/publications#wil15c">ASbase</a> uses AS as the <em>connective fabric</em> for IoT things</li>
					<ul>
						<li>AS has a (social) base vocabulary that can be used for basic functions (such as <q>following</q>)</li>
						<li>AS is extensible with new activities (their identifiers and data models)</li>
					</ul>
					<li><a href="https://github.com/dret/ASDL" title="Activity Streams Documentation Language">ASDL</a> can be used to document extensions in a structured way</li>
					<ul>
						<li>ASDL is not intended to <em>formally describe</em> AS extensions</li>
						<li>It is similar in scope to <a href="https://github.com/dret/sedola" title="Service Documentation Language">Sedola</a> by focusing on making documentation discoverable</li>
					</ul>
				</ul>
			</slide>
		</part>
		<part id="conclusions">
			<title>Conclusions</title>
			<slide>
				<title>Conclusions</title>
				<ul>
					<li>IoT value is multiplied by thinking <em>beyond single IoT islands</em></li>
					<li>WoT can be the SOA solution for interconnecting IoT islands</li>
					<li>WoT is in its infancy and needs experimentation and experience</li>
					<li>Industry wants to sell IoT but has little interest/expertise in WoT</li>
				</ul>
			</slide>
			<slide id="thanks">
				<title>Thanks! Q&amp;A</title>
				<img src="where-to.jpg" title="What's Next?" style="height : 65% ; margin : 4% ; "/>
			</slide>
		</part>
	</presentation>
</hotspot>